<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gluten Free Ideas</title>
    <description>A site to learn how to cook easy GF recipes.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 21:46:37 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 21:46:37 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaded Cod</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Breaded cod accompanied by &lt;a href=&quot;/arugula-mushroom-salad/&quot;&gt;arugula and mushroom salad&lt;/a&gt; offers a lovely variation to prepare fish. It is delicious, healthy and very easy to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lb of cod fish cut in fillets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups of rice flour or your favorite gluten free flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of corn starch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canola oil (as needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the fish in rectangles, approximately 2 or 3 inches per side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a station of three plates: one with corn starch, one with the egg previously whisked and one with the rice flour mixed with sesame seeds, salt, pepper and chili flakes (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each piece of fish will pass through each of the stations: first cover the fish with corn starch, then with egg and finally pass the fish through the rice flour station.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once all the fish is breaded, heat up oil in a deep wok or pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To fry the fish, place each piece of fish in the pot with oil until it is golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/breaded-fish/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/breaded-fish/</guid>
        
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>paleo</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
        <category>sugar-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arugula &amp; Mushroom Salad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out this refreshing salad, wonderful to accompany any type of meats, fish, chicken or just on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 bowl of fresh arugula&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 or 5 white mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chili flakes (optional) to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean and cut the mushrooms in thin slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix in the arugula, already cleaned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the minced garlic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season with the olive oil, lemon juice, salt and chili flakes (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the salt with low sodium salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/arugula-mushroom-salad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/arugula-mushroom-salad/</guid>
        
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>paleo</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brisket &amp; Potatoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We love preparing this recipe for family gatherings and festivities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve the brisket and potatoes accompanied by other side dishes such as salads, &lt;a href=&quot;/fried-eggplant/&quot;&gt;fried eggplant&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/grilled-peppers/&quot;&gt;grilled peppers&lt;/a&gt;, and guacamole. You can find super easy recipes for the side dishes in this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 brisket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lb of potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 garlic head&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 celery sticks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of red wine (may need up to another cup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of water (may need up to another cup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup Paprika (at least)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kosher salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove as much of the extra fat of the brisket as you like. In our case, we like preparing the meat lean.  For this recipe you will only use the lean part. The fat part can be used in other recipes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a big oven pan place the brisket with some oil and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broil for 10 minutes on each side of the brisket and remove from the oven and take the brisket out of the pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn the oven to 315°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare the vegetables: clean the potatoes, peel the garlic and Cut the carrots, onions and celery in large pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place all the veggies, clove and bay leaves in the pan with a bit of salt, pepper and oil and mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the brisket in paprika on both sides and place the brisket back in the pan on top of the vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1 cup of wine and 1 cup of water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the pan with aluminum foil and cook for approximately 45 min per pound of brisket. Halfway make sure there’s enough liquid in the pan and also flip the brisket. If the liquid evaporated, add more, always a mix of water and wine in equal parts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To serve, cut the brisket in slices. This can be done when hot or cold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the Kosher salt with low sodium salt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have leftovers you can use the brisket in sandwiches, fried in the pan, or prepare a hash mixing small pieces of the meat, eggs, onions and potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The leftover juices can be used as stock or thickened with cornstarch and use it as gluten free gravy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/brisket-potatoes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/brisket-potatoes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>paleo</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fried Eggplant Salad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fried eggplant salad is a delicious side dish, very easy to prepare. It can be served on its own, seasoned with salt, pepper and green onions, or can be combined with tahini. Check out both options of and enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium or big black eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup of tahini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lemon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp minced parsley or cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of cold water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kosher salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chili flakes (optional) to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the eggplant and cut it in half inch slices. Then cut each slice into half inch cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pan put 2 tbsp of olive oil in high heat. When hot, add the eggplant cubes.
Mixing the eggplant with a spatula until it is fully cooked (it will look a bit translucent). Once it is cooked, put aside and let it rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fried-eggplant-alone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eggplants Saute&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mince the parsley.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small food processor add the tahini with a 3/4 cup of water, 1 tablespoon of lemon juice, minced garlic and 1teaspoon of salt.Process all the ingredients until obtaining a runny, homogeneous sauce. If the sauce is not runny enough, add 1tablespoon of water and process again. Repeat until reaching the desired consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the cooked eggplant in a plate, add the tahini sauce, chili flakes (optional) and parsley. Mix with a fork until it looks homogenous.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add salt to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the salt with low sodium salt or use just pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/fried-eggplant/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/fried-eggplant/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken skewers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Chicken skewers make such a wonderful main dish. They are so easy to prepare and look so nice either for yourself or when organizing gatherings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound of boneless chicken thighs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 onions (have one more ready just in case)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 peppers (have one more ready just in case)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 white mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metal or wood skewers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kosher salt (to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper (to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika (to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chili flakes (optional, to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean the chicken thighs by removing extra fat and tendons. Cut the chicken in 1 inch cubes (approximately)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the onions and the peppers in one inch cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the mushrooms in quarters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the skewers are made of wood, make sure the skewers have been in cold water for at least 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the skewers are ingredients are cut, using one skewer at a time start “stabbing” a bit of onion with the pointy end and move it down the skewer to become the bottom piece (close to your hand). Keep adding pieces of chicken, pepper, onion and mushroom until being an inch from the top. Close the skewers with another bit of onion (smaller pieces could work well).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle some salt, pepper, paprika and chili flakes (optional) over the skewers. Brush the skewers with the olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking in the BBQ: Preheat the BBQ and place the skewers turning them every 8 min or so until the chicken is well cooked from all sides. Bigger cubes of food may take more time to cook, smaller pieces less.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking in the oven: Preheat the oven to 425°F and follow the same instructions as above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the salt with low sodium salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/chicken-skewers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/chicken-skewers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>paleo</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dark Chocolate Brownies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Craving for cake, something sweet and soft, that also happens to be gluten free and healthy?  This brownies with dark chocolate may just be what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½	cup coconut oil or butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;85 gr unsweetened chocolate (or 3 ounces)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup of honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⅓ cup of coconut flour sifted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp	vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ tsp	baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp	salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 325°F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grease a baking pan with oil or cover with parchment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the unsweetened chocolate with the oil or butter. Place the oil, butter or shortening with the chocolate in a bowl. Place the bowl over a pot of simmering water and whisk the chocolate until all is melted and has a smooth texture.
Alternatively, you can also melt the chocolate in the microwave. See the post with tips on how to melt &lt;a href=&quot;/melt-chocolate/&quot;&gt;chocolate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a mixer, first beat the eggs and honey.  Then, add the coconut flour, the cocoa powder, vanilla, baking soda and salt and beat on low until all ingredients are integrated. Then you can beat on high until you have a smooth mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the melted chocolate until the mix thickens, around 15-20 seconds. Add the chocolate chips and stir them in the mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the batter in the greased pan or pan with parchment. Smooth the top with the spatula or the back of a spoon. Add the walnuts on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 35-45 minutes. To see if it is ready, put a toothpick in the center of the cake. If it comes out clean it is ready. Remove and let it cool for 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the dish to be dairy free use oil instead of butter and use dairy free chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the dish low in sodium replace salt with low-sodium salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/dark-chocolate-brownies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dark-chocolate-brownies/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to melt chocolate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of recipes need melted chocolate. Below are a few ways you can melt the chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use chocolate in bars or in chips format.  If they are in a bar, first cut it in smaller pieces to allow it to melt easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like the mix to be gluten free, make sure you have gluten free chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the melted chocolate to be dairy free, check your chocolate bar or chocolate chips are dairy free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a stove top (or double boiler)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the oil, butter or shortening with the chocolate in a bowl.
Place the bowl over a pot of simmering water and whisk the chocolate until all is melted and has a smooth texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a microwave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the oil, butter or shortening with the chocolate in a bowl.
Microwave the mix in microwave for 30 seconds. Remove, stir the chocolate well.
If the chocolate is not melted, repeat the previous step but for 20 seconds.
If the chocolate started to melt, place the bowl in the microwave for 10-15 seconds bursts until fully melted. Each time, remove from the microwave and stir well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you find them helpful!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/melt-chocolate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/melt-chocolate/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>df</category>
        
        <category>easy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lemonade with ginger and mint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal summer beverage, delicious and refreshing. 
I will present a couple of options to prepare it, as a smoothie or as a  juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 mint branches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lemons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 slices ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups ice cubes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups cold water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sugar, honey or low calorie replacement to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smoothy&quot;&gt;Smoothy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a blender add water, ginger, some mint leaves, the sugar (or honey or low calorie sweetener in a blender). Place the lemons peeled and cut in smaller pieces and finally the ice on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend until you obtain a relatively smooth beverage.  I personally prefer the beverage to have some texture, with more visible ice. Others in the family prefer it smoother, with the ice crushed more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place in a pitcher and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;juice&quot;&gt;Juice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the lemons and cut them in thin slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate the mint leaves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pitcher add all the ingredients: lemon, ginger, mint leaves, sugar (or alternative), ice and water. Mix well and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/lemonade-ginger-mint/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lemonade-ginger-mint/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hummus</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hummus is a dip, spread, or savory dish made from cooked, mashed chickpeas blended with tahini, lemon juice, and garlic. Usually garnished with olive oil, a few whole chickpeas, parsley, and paprika.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups of dry chickpeas (also called garbanzo beans)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 table spoon olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paprika to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parsley (optional for garnish)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of tahini paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ lemon for lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tsp salt (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of the dry chickpeas you can use a can of chickpeas. If so,  start in step 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the chickpeas in a bowl and cover them with water for 1 day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drain the chickpeas, place them in a pot, cover them with water and cook them until they are soft. Let them cool and don’t forget to keep the water used to cook the garbanzo beans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are using chickpeas from a can, drain and rinse the chickpeas. Keep the liquid from the can in a separate container.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tahini sauce: In a food processor put the garlic, lemon juice, tahini, salt and the water from the chickpeas. Two parts of chickpea water for one of tahini. Blend it until you have a homogeneous sauce, for around 1 minute. Voila! Now you have tahini sauce!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chickpeas to the tahini in the processor and blend them until you have an homogeneous consistency. It may take around 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put some hummus on a plate.  To decorate, use the back of a table spoon to smooth the top. Add olive oil and paprika on top. You may also add parsley and some chickpeas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have tahini to spare in case you want more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the salt with low sodium salt or use just pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/hummus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hummus/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tahini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tahini is a savory condiment based on sesame seeds. It is often found in Middle Eastern and Mediterranean cuisine and Asian dishes.  Tahini is super healthy and versatile. It can be used as a spread, a dip, a dressing, and as a key ingredient in other dishes such as hummus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup of tahini paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of cold water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ lemon for lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tsp salt (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a food processor place the garlic, lemon juice, tahini, salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the water (start with half cup and keep adding)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend it until you have a homogeneous sauce. if you prefer the sauce a bit more runny add more water, it will thicken a bit in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voilà! Now you have tahini sauce!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the recipe to be low sodium replace the salt with low sodium salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/Tahini/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Tahini/</guid>
        
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gf</category>
        
        <category>dairy-free</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
